Hi guys, Dr. Burk here. In this video, I
want to talk about will doing a high-fat
ketogenic diet clog your arteries. Now,
just from the pure um observation of
eating more fat and a a fatty clogged
artery, it sounds logical that if you
were to eat more fat, you're going to
get a clogged artery. Okay? It sounds
logical that you would eat more fat and
then get more fat in your body, right?
But that's not how it works in the body
because in the body there are various
hormones that tell certain types of
calories um what to convert into and the
the hormone that tells the body whether
to clog the artery or clean out the
artery really is called insulin. So
insulin is like the switch that converts
fat into the body of storage and also
clogs arteries.
Uh insulin is a very um inflammatory
hormone. If you have too much of it, you
can have a lot more inflammation which
can set you up for a whole series of
events um from the body start healing
the inflammation or the lesion in the
arteries with a combination of
cholesterol as a band-aid, calcium and
fibrous fibbrin which is a kind of a
connect connective tissue to form a
little bit of a clot. So really what
what would started that would be the
high levels of insulin not necessarily
consuming cholesterol. Now cholesterol
is made by every almost every single
cell in the body. Your body makes about
3,000 milligrams of cholesterol every
single day. That 3,000 milligrams of
cholesterol is equal to 300 strips of
bacon. It's equal to about a pound of
butter. It's equal to 14 eggs. So your
body makes a lot of cholesterol. Okay?
So when you consume more fat, your body
just makes more less. Okay? That's how
it works. What really creates this
clogged artery is high levels of insulin
by consuming too many carbohydrates.
Um, so if you were to cut your
carbohydrates down, like the breads,
pasta, cereal, crackers, things like
that, and sugar, if you were to cut that
down, you would notice your cholesterol
would go way down. Also, your
triglycerides would go way down, your
bad cholesterol would go down. But if
you were to increase the sugar and the
insulin, your cholesterol goes up. And
you should even experiment with yourself
to see if this is true for you. Um,